spring has come early to my valley and
diminutive pink and white wild flowers
have bloomed all over the forest floor I
tread lightly these days and with great
reverence as there are so many Treasures
yet to behold I like to snatch away a
few minutes on these cool mornings
before the busyness of the workday sets
in to Express gratitude for all that has
been renewed I don't have much time but
what I do have I value deeply and that
has made all the
difference in this video I wanted to
share something that I've been working
on for a very long time and that is
fixing my attention
span as a child I could become deeply
absorbed in things that interested me
even just watching the sun through a car
window engrossed in an imaginary world
of my creation everything I experienced
I did so in the present moment even if
my curiosity took me somewhere else a
moment later but something happened to
me as I got older and my brain got more
muddled and at times I've had to take
inspiration from the better parts of my
younger self and wonder how I want to
spend the time I have
[Music]
good
I'm out here just enjoying a little bit
of the breeze and the Sunshine and later
this afternoon I'm going to a hair salon
for the first time in a very very long
time I finally decided that um it was
time to cut my hair to give my hair a
chance to grow out again so that is the
plan today to work to get some time
outside to take time to enjoy the spring
beauties that are growing
everywhere to look out for yellow bells
and blue bells cuz I'm sure they're
about to start blooming and to say hello
to the
honeybees I'll probably get a little
more work done but after that I'm going
to go to the hair appointment and I'm a
little bit nervous so wish me luck the
spring beauties are always one of the
very first flowers that come out this
time of year they're very interesting
actually at the very base there is a
root ball called a corn and you can eat
them and I've eaten them before in
videos they are absolutely delicious I
describe them as floral essenced
potatoes
and it's it's a a beautiful flower with
such delicate colors I love the little
tiny hints of
pink as I got older I started to become
more impatient focused on productivity
of saving time to get more done I was
introduced to a much faster pace of Life
partly through starting to use my phone
lot more I grew up with limited internet
but once I entered University and
started realizing I was way behind on
that front I threw myself into the
online world and got my first smartphone
and don't get me wrong I think this has
added to my quality of life I've
connected with other kindred spirits and
learned new things been exposed to ideas
and inspired but I also found how easy
it was to misuse the tools at my
disposal to get to the point where I
gravitated to my phone at every dull
moment scrolled for hours without even
knowing what I was doing half the time
or being able to remember what I watched
or
learned so easily it became a way to
disconnect from the world uncomfortable
emotions boring moments where I would
otherwise have to spend sitting with my
own thoughts the more I used these tools
in an unbalanced way the less I enjoyed
being without
distractions over time my mind started
to struggle to concentrate on less
stimulating tasks I found I was Finding
less joy in things I used to love as a
child I didn't find things as
interesting as I had I felt less peace
in general often Fired Up by the latest
controversial post i' had seen over the
years i' had been spending less and less
time with just me and without even
realizing it I had lost a
friend my ability to pay attention to
things to be present and hold my my own
Focus was increasingly fragmented and
unstable my mind became a buzzing bee of
activity that was relentless and
constantly
distracting sometimes I wanted to avoid
it all
together to be clear I don't blame my
phone or anything else for this change I
noticed I still love using technology of
all kinds I love making videos here on
YouTube I need to connect and I enjoy
every moment as long as I'm using these
tools in balance
that was the key not to look at things
from a black and white perspective but
wonder how can this serve me better and
that answer for me was to become more
intentional with how I interact with my
phone to challenge the idea that I
needed to keep up with what was going on
every minute of the day and I'll be
honest the more addicted I was to living
online the more distractable I became
the more short my attention span I
decided I needed to rethink my
lifestyle every time I get to this stage
in the painting process I just feel like
quitting to be honest um and I don't
really want to do anymore and um I just
want to stop and never finish it um but
I'm going to try to persevere there's
still a lot to do so I'm going to keep
going I did get my hair cut it is not as
short as I was going to cut it but it is
still quite short I think I cut about 6
in off it um which is a lot cuz I have
not cut my hair you know drastically for
many years um but yes I was going to go
shorter but then the woman that was
cutting my hair reminded me that when
you still have very wavy and thick hair
and you cut it very short it has a
tendency to mushroom out I was inspired
this week to think a little bit about
attention spans and how my ability to
focus and more than that more
importantly than that simply my ability
to be
comfortable without huge amount of
stimulation uh with just being um has
been such an important part
in healing and thriving for me it's not
perhaps the most exciting thing to do
with your life to just cut out highly
stimulating things at certain portions
of the day and training yourself to do
kind of more mindful hobbies and more
boring lifestyle choices at times it's
all about balance for sure I think that
technology has a wonderful and important
place in our lives if used well but I
have not always used it in a healthy way
at the time I think over the long term
it created this habit of not observing
not looking outward as much and that was
something that was very unhealthy for me
and did not lead to my long-term joy and
fulfillment and that may be completely
different for you I'm not saying this is
everyone's experience and that this is
an unhealthy thing for everyone um I
just can can only speak my
experience
[Music]
oh
okay well I have procrastinated long
enough it is time to finish this
project if uh you want a wonderful
challenge for improving your internal
dialogue and your inner life I recommend
doing a big painting project without any
distractions because boy you are going
to have to come to terms with all those
thoughts going through your head because
you are literally watching paint dry I'm
going to get back to work but I also
wanted to let you know I do have my Etsy
shop open I am not going to have it open
for too much longer I am expecting baby
soon so I will be closing in several
weeks and I appreciate your support
there if you are interested in my art or
on my patreon where I make extra videos
about simple living there of course is
never any obligation but I always like
to share it as a way to support my work
as an artist and this channel thank you
so much for being here I'm sending you
so so much love and I'm going to go and
finish this
goodbye
now many years later I'm continuing to
learn how to do things differently and
have made enormous progress I've learned
slowing down isn't about what's
happening outside we don't always have
control over that but a shift
within I'm continuing to develop a
balanced relationship with the internet
not to fuel unhealthy mindsets in
comparison and
consumerism once I made a few small
changes I started to become more aware
of what triggered unhelpful feelings and
wanted to weed that out even more and I
think the best part of the process was
that as I distanced myself from the
online world and balanced it the world
started to seem less angry and my mind
stopped feeling exhausted all the time
and I liked that taking Tak a break from
information overwhelm helped my brain
reset and become more quiet more
attentive it became easier to find
Wonder again obviously I love the
internet but I do think it can be
helpful to consider our relationships
with the things we use most in our lives
and make sure they align with how we
want to use the very limited time we
have this personal inquiry started me on
a journey perhaps it will do the same
for you